I've got it.
好
[Meng'an.]
梦安
You lied to me again?
又骗我
Go back home with me!
跟我回家
Meng'an, wait!
梦安
Come with me!
你跟我走
Meng'an!
回家
Meng'an, you...
梦安 你
Come home with me.
跟我回家
Hey, listen to me.
你 你听我说
Just come home.
你跟我回家
Please hear me out.
你听我说
You're a tech guy.
你是干技术的呀
You're supposed to do research.
你是做研究的
This kind of work will wear you down.
你这样会把身体熬坏的
Let's go home.
我们回家
I, I'm...
我我 我没
Come on, let's go.
跟我走 回家
I'm fine.
我没事
Please, come home.
你跟我回家
I'm really not going back.
我真的不回去
Let's go. Come with me.
你跟我回家 跟我走
I'm fine, really. I swear.
我真没事 真没事
Seriously, Meng'an.
真没事 梦安
Meng'an, Meng'an.
梦安 梦安
Come home with me.
跟我回家
Let's just go home.
回家吧
Meng'an, don't cry, please.
梦安 不哭不哭
I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm truly sorry, Meng'an, I...
对不起 梦安 我
I've let you down again.
我又让你失望了
I'm sorry I disappointed you.
对不起 我让你失望了
But I still want to try.
但我还是想尽力
I,
我
I still want to
我还是想
work hard to make you
努力地让咱们这个家
feel safe
有安全
and give you a better life.
有奔头
I can't
这个家
put all the weight on your shoulders.
不能够只靠你一个人
You've got me too.
还有我
Just give me another chance.
再给我一次机会
I know.
我知道
I know, I know.
我知道 我知道
Please, just listen.
你听我说
This is the hardest time
这是我这一辈子
of my life.
最难的时候
But I won't give up.
但我不会放弃
I won't quit.
我不会放弃
I still want to
我还是想尽力地
try my best
努力地
to be
成为一个合格的
a good husband
好丈夫
and a loving dad.
好父亲
Just give me some time.
你再给我点时间
Please.
好吧
Everything will be fine.
一切都会好起来的
Hello?
喂
Is this Ms. Mei?
是梅一朵师姐吗
[Hi, it's Xu Meng'an.]
你好 我是许梦安
Li Lin's wife.
李临的太太
Do you remember me?
你还记得我吗
Xu Meng'an?
许梦安
It's been a while.
好久不见
Last time I was back from abroad,
我上次回国的时候
I saw Li Lin.
见到李临了
We even talked about you.
我们还聊起你了呢
Thanks.
谢谢啊
Yeah, well,
是这样
I need to
有个事情
[ask you a favor.]
我想麻烦你
What is it?
什么事啊
Li Lin
李临
lost his job.
失业了
What?
李临失业了
How?
怎么会
It was pretty sudden.
就挺突然的
When he went to Beijing
上次他去北京
to visit you last time,
找你的时候
he might've been hoping you could help.
可能就是想请你帮忙
But,
但是
maybe because you're an old classmate,
可能是因为老同学
he couldn't bring himself to ask.
就没好意思开口
So I mean,
我是想说
I'm asking now
我想替他
for him
问问你
is there any job
有没有合适的工作
that might suit him.
可以介绍给他
No wonder when we
难怪上次我们
met last time,
见面的时候
he seemed a bit off.
我觉得他有些奇怪
[It was like he was trying to hint]
他似乎好像拐弯抹角地
[that he wanted]
跟我说
[to make a career change.]
想突破一下现在的工作
I even advised him
我当时还劝他
to wait for the right moment.
要等待最好的时机
If that's the case,
那如果是这样的话
finding a job
找工作的事情
is pretty urgent now.
就比较紧迫了
Yeah.
是
I, I am hoping
我想 我想麻烦你
maybe in your field
有没有你们原来的专业
there is something he could do
能够让他参与啊
or someone you could refer him to.
或者是介绍
If not,
如果要是没有的话
anything else would help.
其他的也行
Well, I just...
反正这个事 就
I really don't know who else to turn to.
我也不知道该找谁帮忙
So I thought
就想
you might help him out.
请你帮帮他
Don't worry.
你放心
I'd totally help you.
这个忙我一定帮
Thanks a lot.
谢谢啊
Can you keep it between us
我给你打电话的事
that I called?
能不跟李临说吗
Sure.
好
Thanks, I really appreciate it.
好 谢谢
You're up.
醒了
What are you doing here?
你怎么来了
I was craving your wontons.
想吃碗您煮的馄饨
I'll make some for you.
爸给做去啊
Why do Xin and I
为什么我跟心心的
always have one egg
馄饨里面
in our wontons
永远只有一个鸡蛋
but Mom gets two?
我妈的就有两个呀
Because your mom bore me two daughters.
因为你妈生了俩姑娘
I'm good now.
我好了
Then you should head back.
好了就回去吧
You still need to
一会儿还得
get Yunjie to school later.
送孩子上学呢
And your mom's gonna wake up.
要不你妈该醒了
Go on.
回吧
Director Xu,
许总监
the bidding's about to start.
投标时间快到了
We need to go now.
我们得走了
We're gonna win, right?
我们会成功的吧
We've worked so hard.
我们已经很努力了
Hard work doesn't always
很多事情不是你努力了
guarantee success.
就会成功的
People say
他们说
if you don't try, you'll never succeed.
不努力就一定不会成功
My mom always told me to
我妈也说
never pass up a chance
一定不要放弃任何一个
to give it my all.
需要努力的机会
But I still want to try.
但我还是想尽力
I,
我
I still want to
我还是想
work hard to make you
努力地让咱们这个家
feel safe
有安全
and give you a better life.
有奔头
[I can't]
这个家
[put all the weight on your shoulders.]
不能够只靠你一个人
Let's go.
我们走
Mr. Yu,
于总
you're really dedicated.
够敬业的呀
Showing up for the bidding yourself.
投标会都自己来了
You guys go on ahead and get ready.
你们先上去准备一下
Wait, wait.
等等 等等
I
我
need to tell you something.
有个事得跟你说
You two go in first.
你们俩先进去吧
What's the matter?
怎么了
[Why so hesitant?]
吭吭唧唧的
You're wearing the ring.
戒指戴上了
[Glad that you took my advice.]
挺听劝哪
Good for you.
值得表扬
Yeah, I'm wearing it,
戴是戴上了
but Wanzhen still
但是婉真
wants a divorce.
要跟我离婚
If she said that,
那她要是这么说了
she is serious about it.
肯定就是想好了呗
The paperwork's already started.
已经开始走流程了
But I don't want a divorce.
但是我不想离啊
Why didn't you realize that sooner?
那你早干吗去了
I know, I messed up.
是 我错了
I messed up everything.
我全都错了
Can you talk to her?
你帮我劝劝她呗
No way.
劝不了
You two are best friends, aren't you?
你们俩不是闺蜜吗
Yeah,
是啊
we are.
是闺蜜
But we're also
但我们也是
mature, independent women
可以为自己行为
and take responsibility for our choices.
负责任的成熟女性
We're not going to change
不会因为别人的
major life choices
一两句话就改变自己
just because someone says so.
人生的重大决定的
Wanzhen means what she says.
婉真这个人 说到做到
I'm sure she gave you chances,
我相信肯定给过你机会
but you didn't take them.
只是你没珍惜罢了
I'm heading in now.
我先过去了啊
Yes, this is Huaxing Real Estate.
是的 华謃地产
Wanzhen,
婉真
don't forget to bring the materials
别忘了 两点
to the meeting room at 2 p.m.
把材料送到会议室去啊
Got it.
知道
Thank you.
辛苦你了
Don't mention it.
没事
Wanzhen,
婉真姐
where should I put these boxes?
来的这批纸盒放哪儿啊
Just set them on the table.
放那台上吧
I'll handle it.
我来吧
Madam,
姐
where should I put this bottled water?
咱们那个水放哪儿啊
Follow me.
跟我来
Okay.
好
[Wanzhen.]
婉真姐
Put it in the beverage bar over there.
放那水吧
Okay.
好
Here's a document.
这里有一份资料
I need ten copies of it.
要复印十份
Meng'an,
梦安
what brings you here?
你怎么来了
Why didn't you tell me
你出了这么大的事
something this big happened?
怎么不告诉我呢
I just started this new job,
我这不刚开始工作吗
and I've been swamped.
忙得焦头烂额的
No time to catch up.
没空约你
I thought I should
我觉得这事儿
tell you this in person.
还得当面跟你说
So you really wanna divorce him?
真打算离了
You heard it from Yu Hai?
听于海说的
I ran into him
今天投标的时候
at the bidding today.
碰见他了
He said he doesn't want the divorce
他说他不想离
and asked me to talk to you.
让我劝劝你
I refused, though.
我没答应啊
You know me so well.
还是你了解我
Have you
那你这是
made up your mind?
想好了
If you were in my shoes,
你要是在我的处境里
you'd make the same choice, right?
你也会这么选择 对吧
Probably.
应该吧
In your marriage,
在你们俩的婚姻里边
Yu Hai was the one who messed up.
出错的是于海
He should face the consequences.
这个后果他也应该承担
I've got your back.
我支持你
Just tell me if you need anything.
需要我做什么 尽管说
I'm moving out the day after tomorrow.
我后天一早搬家
Are you going with me?
陪我一起啊
Where are you moving?
搬哪儿啊
To an apartment downtown.
就市区的公寓
It's not far from here.
离这儿不远
I've already packed up.
都收拾好了
So, will you come?
要不要去嘛
Of course.
那肯定啊
That's great.
太好了
Seeing you doing well,
不过看你状态不错
I'm relieved.
我也就放心了
Is the Wendy Chen excelling
那个叱咤职场的温蒂陈
in the finance world making a comeback?
是不是要回来了
[Please don't kick me out,]
求你别赶我走
[for the sake of our son!]
就看在孩子的面上
[You wanna talk to me about the kid?]
你还好意思提孩子啊
[I agreed to move out]
当初我同意搬走
[to protect him]
就是怕咱俩的事
[from this.]
影响孩子
And now you do such disgusting things?
现在你干这种恶心的事
[Stop the car.]
停一下车
[Did you even think about our son?]
你考虑过孩子的感受吗
[Honey,]
老公
[I didn't hurt Haoze!]
我没影响到孩子呀
[I'm done talking.]
我不想再跟你废话了
[Are you leaving or not?]
你现在走不走
[If you don't go,]
你要是不走
[I'm calling the cops.]
我可报警了
Call the cops if you want!
你报警就报警
This is my home too.
这也是我的家
Why should I leave?
凭什么让我走
[Look at you, looking all glamorous.]
你看你现在人模狗样的
Don't forget
你别忘了你怎么
how you got here.
混到今天的
Why is
这个家为什么
this family broken?
变成这样了
Thanks to you.
还不是因为你
[Have you ever thought about]
你考虑过
[what this does to me and Haoze?]
我跟孩子的脸面吗
[When I asked you]
当初我让你
[to sign the divorce papers,]
签离婚协议时候
[why didn't you do it?]
你为什么不签
For our son,
为了孩子
I gave you
我已经给你
a decent life.
很体面的生活
[You should've just behaved yourself]
你就本本分分
[and taken care of Haoze.]
把孩子带好就行了
[And look what you've done.]
你现在干的什么事
You have to leave today.
你今天必须滚出去
Get out!
滚
Are you driving me out
就是为了这个贱人
for this bitch?
你就想把我逼走
Is that it?
是不是
[It's all for her, isn't it?]
你就是为了她 是不是
[Enough!]
别吵了
This is a classy neighborhood.
这里是高档社区
Mind your language, will you?
注意素质行吗
Take it up with the lawyer.
有什么事找律师聊吧
[It's you again.]
又是你啊
Mrs. Jia,
贾太太
hello, hello.
你好你好你好
You're the one who
浩泽妈妈的事情
exposed Haoze's mom's secret, right?
是你捅出去的
Why would you ruin others' families?
你怎么破坏别人家庭啊
I was just doing
我这是受人之托
what I was asked.
忠人之事
[Mrs. Jia,]
贾太太
contact me
您有什么事
if you need anything.
记得联系我
I'm always at your service.
随时为您服务
Thanks.
谢谢
Landing this bid
这个标啊
was perfect timing.
中得太及时了啊
It gave Xinmiao
让我们新苗呢
a real boost.
又回了一口血
Meng'an, well done.
梦安 辛苦了
Thank you.
不辛苦
But it's really thanks to your sharp eye
主要还是您慧眼如炬
for picking such a great project.
能挑到这么好的项目
Mr. Yu from Blue Ocean led his team.
蓝海的于总 亲自带队
But they couldn't beat Meng'an.
都没有赢过梦安
Great job!
好
It was a team effort.
这是大家的功劳啊
Teamwork makes all the difference.
还是团队力量大嘛
And of course, we have a great leader.
还有您 领导有方啊
Exactly.
也对
Everyone,
大家啊
let's stay united
以后还要精诚团结
and keep working hard.
共同努力啊
Let's keep it up!
加油
The boss is in a good mood today,
今天老板高兴
and he'll treat us to afternoon tea!
请大家喝下午茶
Fine, fine.
好好
It's on me.
请请请 请
Meng'an,
梦安
come on in.
快来快来
Take a seat.
快坐
Mr. Zhang,
张总
I want to discuss something with you.
想跟您商量个事
What is it?
商量什么啊
No need for discussion.
不用商量
You're in charge.
你说了算
You're the big hero of our company.
你是公司的大功臣现在
I'm flattered.
您千万别这么说
Come on, have a seat.
你快 坐坐坐 坐
So, here's the thing.
是这样哈
I'd like to take some time off.
我想跟您请个假
When?
什么时候
Next week.
下周
How many days?
几天啊
I was hoping to use up
我 我想把之前的
leftover annual vacation days.
年假都补齐
That's... not going to work.
那那 那不行
We're in the middle of a critical time.
你现在什么时候啊
And you want to take vacation now? You...
你还休年假 你这
It's not like that.
不是
I really have something urgent.
我真的是有急事
Oh, come on.
你得 得了吧
You just want a raise,
你不就是
don't you?
涨钱是吧
No, it's not like that.
不是 不是
Fine, fine, you'll get a raise.
涨涨涨 给你涨
A raise?
涨
Seriously?
真涨啊
You don't know
你这 你自己
what you want.
要什么都不确定
So...
你这
Well, I still want to take the vacation.
那我 我还是要假吧
When will you let me
那您什么时候
have some time off?
能让我休这个假呀
Didn't I just give you
我这不是给了你
two projects?
两个项目吗
You nailed the first one,
第一个完成得非常好
and you need to
下边的这个
finish the other one too.
你得接着来啊
[I can't trust anyone else with it.]
我交给别人我又不放心
Once these two projects are done,
等把这两个项目忙完了
you can take your annual vacation.
你就踏踏实实地休年假
Deal?
行不行
[I promise I won't go back on it.]
我绝不食言
Alright.
行
See?
你看看
It's the long-time employees
还得是一起
that I can always count on.
创业的老员工
You're the one who can get the job done.
这风格就是高
Alright, get back to work.
那行 你忙去吧
Okay, I'll head out now.
那 那我出去了哈
Dad.
爸
An,
安安
come home for dinner this weekend.
周末回来吃饭啊
Your dad made your favorite
你爸给你做了最爱吃的
fried ribbonfish.
炸带鱼
I'll go buy a softshell turtle later
我一会儿去买个甲鱼
[and make some nourishing soup for you.]
给你煲汤补一补啊
I think I'll pass.
我 就不了吧
I have to work overtime.
我要加班
Let Li Lin and Yunjie go instead.
叫李临和云阶回去吧
You're not coming home?
你不回来呀
Then they don't have to come either.
那他们俩也别回了
What's that supposed to mean?
几个意思啊
[You're not letting them come home?]
都不让李临他们回家了
No.
不是
I wanted to make this soup
我煲这个甲鱼汤
to boost your health.
我是想给你补一补
[They don't need it.]
他们俩不用补
I'm just fine.
我身体挺好的
I don't need it, either.
不用补啊
Fine? How?
好什么呀
Last time you came back,
你上次回来
didn't you say
不说那 那什么
you're in menopause?
什么 更年期了吗
No,
没有
it's...  just a common condition.
就 就是常见病
With the way you're talking,
你这么说
I still don't buy it.
我有点不信
It's nothing, Mom.
真没有 妈
It's just that
就是
I'm in my forties now,
我四十多岁了
so it's normal to have
身体有点小毛病
some minor health problems.
也是很正常的
Isn't it?
是不是
Then send me
那你把那个病历本
your medical records.
发过来我看看
There's no medical records.
没有病历本
It was just the annual company
就是公司每年例行的
physical exam.
身体检查
Nothing to worry about.
真的没事
The more you talk, the less I'm convinced.
你越这么说我越不踏实
[I feel like you're]
我觉得你有什么事
[hiding something.]
瞒着我
[Just send over the report...]
你把那个体检
Alright, I gotta go.
咱不说了
I'll send you
我把体检报告
the full report
挨页挨页地
page by page.
给你们发过去
Alright?
行吧
I think you're just exhausted.
我看你 你就是累的
Last time you came home, you looked pale.
你看上次回来脸都绿了
How could I look that bad?
我怎么能绿呢
If anyone is in trouble, it must be...
要绿也是
No,
不是
nobody's getting...
这谁也不能绿呀
[Let's just drop it.]
咱不说了
[I'm still at work.]
我这还上着班呢
[Is that okay?]
好不好
[I'll try to come home this weekend.]
周末我就争取回去
And let's skip the turtle soup.
那个 甲鱼就不做了啊
I'm hanging up now.
我挂了
Pale?
绿
That's not good.
不能
Let's go.
走
Where to?
干啥去
To buy the softshell turtle.
买甲鱼去
She's not even coming home.
人家都不回来了
Why bother buying it?
买什么甲鱼啊
We'll get it now and keep it in the pool.
先买着 放池子里养着
When she comes back,
她什么时候回来
I'll cook it for her.
什么时候给她做
Don't bother.
别买了
Are you coming or not?
你去不去
Alright, alright, I'm coming.
去去去 去去去
Wait a second.
等一会儿
I need to get ready.
我去准备一下
Hurry up.
快点
I'll make sure we've got everything.
装备要齐
Hey, Wanzhen.
婉真
Meng'an.
梦安
I saw a car leaving
我刚才来的时候
when I got here.
看见一个车已经出去了
Am I too late?
我是不是来晚了
No worries.
没事
There wasn't much stuff to move anyway.
又没多少东西
Where's Yu Hai?
于海呢
Busy with work.
公司忙着呢
Not even showing up when you're leaving?
搬家都不出现吗
How are things
你俩现在
between you two?
到哪步了
We're in the middle of the process.
正在走流程呢
I'm moving out first.
我先搬出去吧
Is he stalling
他该不会是
on the divorce?
拖着不想离吧
I already discussed it
我提这个事
with the lawyer.
是和律师商量过的
He's raising funds right now.
他现在正融资呢
To protect his shares,
为了保全股份
he's likely to agree.
应该会同意的
You know,
男人嘛
men always put work first.
事业总是第一位的
I should learn from him on that.
这一点我应该向他学习
[I'm here!]
我来啦
Hi, Xin.
心心啊
Meng'an.
姐
No need to hurry.
你慢点
It's alright.
没事
Why'd you come empty-handed?
怎么空着手就来了
How's that possible? It's all in the car.
瞧不起谁呢 在车上呢
[So where's the new place?]
新家在哪儿呢
Wanna check it out?
想看啊
Of course.
当然
Let's go.
走
Didn't you say this was the new place?
不是说是新家吗
It's nicely decorated.
你这装扮得也太好了吧
Actually, I bring the kids
其实偶尔
over sometimes.
也会带孩子过来住一住
And you never invited me?
那你没邀请过我
Where's the kids' room?
儿童房在哪儿呢
Over there.
那间
I've gotta see
我得看看两个孩子
where the two kids are sleeping.
是怎么住的
Feeling down?
受委屈了
No, I'm fine. Everything will get better.
不委屈 会好起来的
I should be thanking you
我还得谢谢你呢
for helping me
替我找了一份
find a stable job.
踏实的工作
That's a lovely place.
真不错
And I need to thank Mengxin too,
还有梦心
for helping me with the kids lately.
你最近帮我照顾孩子
So
所以呢
I can focus on my work.
我才能安心地工作啊
Don't mention it.
你跟我客气什么呀
They're all classmates.
他们都是同学嘛 是吧
If you need anything,
有什么事
just call me.
随时给我打电话
Okay.
行嘞
I love your apartment!
我太喜欢你这房子了
It's so cozy and comfortable.
这又温馨又舒服的
It's good to have a place like this.
有一个这样的小地儿
I'm going to talk to Haowen
我得跟老贾商量一下
about buying one too.
我也要买个公寓
In case we ever have a fight,
万一跟他吵架了
I'll have somewhere to go.
我也有个地方待着
Even if you have a fight,
你跟老贾吵架
he'd be the one to get kicked out.
也只有他躲出去的份吧
Doesn't matter.
那我不管
I still want
那我也要有一个
my own space.
自己的空间
Aren't you in real estate?
你不是在地产公司吗
Help me find an apartment, will you?
你帮我物色一下呗
No problem.
没问题呀
Why do you need so many houses?
你买那么多房干吗呀
You can never have too many.
房子谁嫌多呀
They're solid investments
这真金白银买的
and hold their value.
搁那儿还能保值呢
See?
看到了吗
That's the gap between the rich and the poor.
这就是贫富差异
They buy a house on a whim,
人家随随便便买套房
For salaried folks like us,
我们这种打工族
even with the whole family chipping in,
举全家之力
we can barely afford the down payment.
也就勉强付个首付
A house is just a house.
房子只是房子
As long as you're with
只要和心爱的人
someone you love,
在一起住啊
that's what makes it a home.
那才叫家
That's correct.
说得没错
Come on.
来来来
Let's cut the cake
切蛋糕
to celebrate you moving into a new place.
庆祝你的乔迁之喜
Starting today,
从今天开始
I'm beginning my
我要开启我的
new life!
新生活
Mengxin's gone.
梦心都走了
Why are you still hanging around?
你还杵这儿干什么呀
I was just thinking I'd help you
我这不想再帮你
tidy up a bit.
收拾收拾吗
Nonsense.
收拾什么呀
Spill the truth.
说实话吧
What's up?
怎么了
I don't have much time.
我可没有多少时间啊
I've got to pick up the kids later.
一会儿要去接孩子
I'm pregnant.
怀孕了
Congrats!
恭喜啊
You and Li Lin must be in great shape.
你跟李临这身体不错呀
At your age, getting pregnant is not easy.
说怀就怀了
You didn't go for IVF, did you?
不是试管吧
IVF? Please.
你才试管呢
We're just healthy.
身体好就是身体好
That's all.
瞧不起谁呢
That's impressive.
佩服 佩服
Well,
那个
why don't we call Mengxin over?
把梦心叫过来呗
This is worth celebrating.
咱们再庆祝一下
No, no, no.
别别别
I haven't told her.
没跟她说
They don't know yet.
他们都不知道呢
Right, right.
对对对
Better not to tell in the first three months.
三个月前不能说
How far along?
那你这几个月了
When's the due date?
预产期什么时候啊
I don't want this baby.
没想要
Why not?
为什么呀
[Getting pregnant at your age isn't easy.]
你这年龄怀孕不容易
That is a good thing.
这是好事啊
Why wouldn't you want it?
怎么就不想要了
What's good about it?
好什么呀
Ever since
打从知道
I found this out,
有这个孩子之后
I've been torn.
我就一直纠结着
We just can't afford it.
条件不允许呗
But aren't you and Li Lin
你跟李临生活条件
doing fine?
不是挺好的吗
That was before.
那是以前
Li Lin lost his job.
李临失业了
I'm the only one supporting the family.
现在家里就靠我一个人
If it weren't for
前段时间
my parents helping out,
要不是父母帮衬着
we couldn't even pay the mortgage.
连房贷都还不起了
Even though he's unemployed,
不是失业了
he can find another job.
可以再找工作
He's been looking for months.
他都找了好几个月了
Now he's working at a delivery station.
现在在快递站呢
What does Li Lin think?
那李临怎么说
I haven't told him.
我没告诉他
Meng'an,
梦安
having a baby
这生孩子啊
isn't a small matter.
不是小事啊
I'm not going to
我现在
tell you what to do,
先不劝你生不生
but let me tell you
我先跟你说一说
about Yu Hai and me.
我跟于海的事吧
[Do you know why I]
你知道我为什么
[have to divorce him?]
一定要跟于海离婚吗
Because I don't think
因为我没有觉得
being with him
两个人生活
is better than being on my own.
比一个人更好
All these years,
这些年
he's been wrapped up in his work,
他一直在外面忙工作
and I've been
我呢
left to eat alone,
一个人吃饭
sleep alone,
一个人睡觉
and raise our children alone.
一个人带孩子
In that house,
在这个家里
I couldn't even
我根本就没有感觉到
feel his presence.
他的存在
[But that's just the surface.]
这只是你们看到的表象
[The real problem is,]
其实他真正影响到的是
we don't talk anymore.
我们之间根本没有交流
We're like strangers.
甚至到了形同陌路
[But you and Li Lin are different.]
可是你跟李临不一样
[You've always had a strong bond]
你们俩感情一直很好
[and support each other.]
也是一直相互帮衬着
Don't let a secret like this
不要因为一时的隐瞒
come between
让你们夫妻之间
you two.
有了隔阂
Besides,
再说了
he's your husband
他是你丈夫
and the baby's father.
也是孩子的父亲
At least,
他至少
he deserves to know.
是有知情权的
Heading to the delivery station again?
又要去快递站吗
Yeah, I'm on shift tonight.
今天我当班
But I'll be back in the morning
不耽误明天早上回来
to make breakfast for Yunjie.
给云阶做早餐
[You get some rest.]
你早点休息
Can't you skip tonight?
能不能别去了
Night shifts are really exhausting.
夜班太熬人了
At least ask them to
哪怕你跟他们说
switch you to days.
换个白班呢
All the deliveries come in at night.
接货不都是晚上吗
If I worked days,
要是白班
I'd have to be a delivery rider.
就得做骑手了
And the hours wouldn't work.
那时间不合适
Who'd take care of Yunjie?
谁来照顾云阶啊
[Don't worry about it.]
你放心吧
Just get some sleep.
你 你赶紧睡吧
Has anyone called you
都没有人给你打电话
for an interview?
叫你去面试吗
Take a rest.
你睡觉吧
I'm leaving now.
我走了
Wait, don't go yet.
你先别走
There's something I need to tell you.
我有事要跟你说
You're pregnant?
怀孕了
So, you're really pregnant.
还真怀孕了
I had a feeling before.
我之前就有预感
What feeling?
预感什么呀
I don't want this baby.
我不想要
Why not?
为什么
What do you mean why?
什么为什么呀
I just don't.
就是不想要呗
With our financial situation,
家里这种情况
it's impossible to have another child.
也没法要啊
We're struggling to raise one kid...
养一个孩子还都
How can we handle two?
何况养两个呢
But honey,
不是 老婆
we can make it work.
我们 可以争取一下
Make what work?
争取什么呀
Having a second child?
生二胎吗
You're unemployed.
你现在失业
If I were to be on maternity leave,
然后我在家待产
where would we get the money?
家里吃什么呀
What would we live on?
喝什么呀
I've made up my mind.
这个事情我已经想好了
[This is how it has to be.]
就这样吧
I'll find a time
找个时间
and get the abortion.
去把手术做了
Don't.
不
The situation at home is one thing,
家里的情况是一回事
but this is a big decision.
但这毕竟是个大事
We can't
我们千万不要
rush into it.
草率地做决定
Let's think it over.
我们再想想
I'm done thinking.
不想想了
Let's take some more time.
再想想
[Drive that way, head to the front.]
往那儿 头冲那儿
[Back it up!]
倒
Back! Go, go, go!
倒 倒倒倒
Good.
好
Xiongxiong's asleep.
熊熊睡了
Hold on.
等一下啊
Almost done.
马上
Okay.
好嘞
All set.
好了
Go ahead.
您随便玩
Feel free to browse through it.
您随便看
You don't have another phone, do you?
你不会有别的手机吧
Babe,
我的大宝贝
I'm all yours.
我人都是你的
Think about it.
你想
You're carrying
咱们家的二宝贝
our second baby.
还在你的肚子里呢
How could I be
我怎么可能沾花惹草
fooling around?
偷鸡摸狗呢
I wouldn't do that.
不可能
Fine. l gotta tell you something.
行 那我跟你商量个事
Go ahead.
说
I want to buy an apartment.
我要买一套公寓
Sweetheart,
宝贝
we already have such a big house.
咱们家这么大的房子
Why get an apartment?
买什么公寓啊
It's cramped, not right for you.
多憋屈你 不合适
I need my own space,
我要有一个自己的空间
a place to clear my head.
静一静
I need a backup plan.
我要有个后路
In case,
万一
some day you...
万一你以后
Don't cry, baby.
别哭别哭 宝宝
That's not going to happen.
没有那个万一
I, I'm not that kind of guy.
我 我不是那个渣男
That's impossible.
不可能
There won't be such a day.
没有那个万一
If that day ever comes,
要真有那一天的话
I promise,
我告诉你
the house, the car, and the savings
房子车子存款
are all yours.
全是你的
I'll walk away with nothing.
我净身出户
Don't make empty promises.
别给我画饼
Just tell me if you agree.
你就说同不同意
I agree.
同意
Your word is my command.
什么事我都同意你
Now that's more like it.
那还差不多
I'm going to shower.
我洗澡去了
Go ahead.
去吧
Alright.
好嘞
Shower time.
洗澡去了
Jia Haowen!
贾浩文
Coming!
来啦
What is it?
您说
You're agreeing to everything I say.
我什么要求你都答应我
Do you have something to hide?
你不会是心里有鬼吧
I'll be screwed.
我见鬼去喽
Screwed?
见鬼
Why did he say that?
见什么鬼啊
Is he really hiding something?
还是心里有鬼
[Alright, kids,]
宝贝们
from now on, the three of us
以后我们三个人
are going to sleep
都要生活在
in this room together.
这个房间里了
Do you like it here?
喜不喜欢这儿啊
Yes!
喜欢
As long as I'm with Mom, I'll love it.
跟妈妈在一起都喜欢
Really?
真的啊
Of course.
当然
But Mom,
可是妈妈
why are we moving
你为什么要和我们一起
into this small apartment?
搬到这个小房子里啊
Because I
因为妈妈
need to work now.
以后就要工作了
And besides, I can't
再说了 那么大的房子
afford the big house anymore.
妈妈负担不起啊
Mom,
妈妈
are you really going to leave Dad?
你真的要和爸爸分开吗
A divorce?
离婚
Like Sarah's parents?
就像莎拉家那样
Yes,
对
that's right.
你们说对了
But,
可是
Dad's always been good to us.
爸爸明明对我们很好啊
And he'll still
那爸爸以后
be good to you.
也会对你们很好啊
Mom,
妈妈
are you leaving Dad
你是为爸爸只工作
because he is a workaholic
不回家
and doesn't come home?
才和他离婚的吗
Not exactly.
也不是
How do I explain this to you?
怎么跟你们说呢
Do you have
你们有没有这样的
such friends
朋友啊
who were really close
就是以前很好
but then slowly
但是慢慢地
grew apart?
就不好了
Yes.
有
Yeah, I do.
有 有
When you're elder,
等你们长大一点
I'll explain
然后妈妈呢
what happened
再给你们讲
between me and Dad, okay?
和爸爸的事 好不好
Mom,
妈妈
do you have to work every day?
你每天都要上班吗
Yes, just like you go to school,
对 跟你们上学一样啊
I have to work from Monday to Friday.
周一到周五
And you'll need to take the school bus.
那你们还要坐校车呢
No more sleeping in.
不许睡懒觉了
And don't be late.
不许迟到
Got it?
听见没有
Yes.
好
But isn't working
但是上班
Dad's job?
不是爸爸做的事吗
How can you say that?
你怎么能这样说呀
Mom can work too.
妈妈不可以上班吗
A lot of classmates'
很多同学的妈妈
moms work, right?
也是要上班的呀
Yes.
是的
My job
妈妈以前的工作呢
used to be
就是
taking care of you two little ones.
照顾你们两个小宝贝
But now you're
可是你们现在是
big girls in second grade.
二年级的大姑娘了
So don't you think
那妈妈是不是
it's time I had a new role too?
也应该有新的任务了
Mom, I support you.
妈妈 我支持你
I support you even more.
我更支持妈妈
My sweethearts,
宝贝
I love you so much.
太爱你们啦
You're the best kids
你们是世界上
in the world.
最好的宝宝
Come here,
来
Mommy loves you.
妈妈爱你们
What? Didn't I tell you
不是 我不都说了吗
even if something serious happens today,
今天就是天塌下来的事
don't call me?
也别给我打电话吗
But, Mr. Yu,
不是 于总
it's about
是耀辉投资
Yaohui Investments.
那边的事啊
What's the problem?
怎么说
It seems
耀辉公司的周总
Mr. Zhou of Yaohui Investments
好像
isn't too interested
对咱们公司
in our company.
不是太感兴趣啊
I see.
我知道了
[Welcome, Mr. Zhou.]
周总来了
[Your reserved bottle, sir.]
您的存酒
Mr. Zhou,
周总
Zhou Yao, right?
周耀是吧
And you are?
你是
Yu Hai,
于海
from Blue Ocean Media.
蓝海传媒的于海
It rings a bell.
想起来了
That media company.
那家传媒公司
I'll have what he's having.
我来杯一样的
Sorry, sir.
对不起 先生
That's Mr. Zhou's private reserve.
这是周先生存的酒